Naveen Kairamkonda

Looking for a fascinating opportunity as a Front End Developer.

(91) 8341084619 naveen2379@gmail.com

Hyderabad

SUMMARY

Strong knowledge in development of rich user experienced web applications using ReactJS framework, using ReactJS with Redux flow, and using React Hooks with TDD (Test Driven Development) approach, HTML, CSS.

Good understanding in consuming and working with RESTful web services, third-party libraries and code integration using git.

Proficient in development of web applications using ArcGIS API for JavaScript and Web appBuilder tool for ArcGIS.

Intrigued in finding breakthroughs for the real-time problems that benefit at a large scale.

EDUCATION

International Institute Of Information Technology(RGUKT), Basar — B Tech

June 2011 - May 2015

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science with an CGPA of 7.68

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Private Limited, Hyderabad — *Project Associate*

Nov 2020 - present,

Client: AmeriPrise Financial Inc.

Wipro Technologies, Hyderabad — Software Engineer

Aug 2015 - Feb 2019,

Client: Melbourne Water Corporation, Australia.

PROJECTS

VCS-UI

Description: Used Github api to show trending developers with their

SKILLS

ReactJS

React with Redux

React Hooks

JavaScript

TDD (Test Driven
Development) using Jest &
Enzyme

HTML

CSS

ArcGIS API for JavaScript

TOOLS

Intellij IDEA

Git

ESRI Products: Web appBuilder for ArcGIS, Portal for ArcGIS, ArcGIS Online, ArcGIS Server, ArcGIS for Desktop (ArcMap, Arc Catalog)

Story Maps, GeoForm

PLATFORMS

Linux, Windows

LANGUAGES

English, Telugu, Hindi

repository name & it's gitHub link, and search functionality using gitHub's username and showing their repositories and implemented a filter functionality to show specific repositories based on the chosen language.

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Naveen2379/vcs-ui

Technologies used: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Winemart

Description: It's a wine mart application, where I have used cocktaildb.com api to retrieve different kinds of wines information(alcoholic, non-alcoholic, etc) available and wine preparation information, etc.

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Naveen2379/winemart-ecommerce

Technologies used: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Travel Website

Description: This web app is designed for the travellers providing possible routes and other info like nearby visiting places, restaurants for that particular trip. Used the Mapbox GL api to show places in the map environment. Used Nodejs, Express server, and mongodB as backend, we have to run the server to get the static route information data from it.

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Naveen2379/travelwebsite-explore

Technologies used: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TDD, Mapbox GL API

DSS (Developer Services System) — GIS

Description: This project aims to provide an approval procedure for users to develop a land (building) and evaluates the business rules given by the Melbourne Water. If the user's application satisfies the rules, will be given permission to develop.

Technologies used: Web appBuilder, Portal for ArcGIS, ArcGIS Server

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Developed new widgets, themes & customized various widgets
 (in-panel/off-panel) to precisely meet the business requirements
 and developed an attractive user interface using Web appBuilder for
 ArcGIS (runs on HTML,ArcGIS API for JavaScript).
- Configuration of theme and widgets using Web appBuilder for ArcGIS.
- Publishing of Map Services, Geocode Services to ArcGIS Server from ArcGIS Desktop & creating Web Mapping Applications, Web Maps and making them available on ArcGIS Online/Portal for ArcGIS.

 Preparing Technical Design Document and documenting test cases for the developed functionalities and testing the application thoroughly in SIT and UAT environments.

Liveability — Our Space Your Place – *GIS*

Link:

http://melbournewater.maps.arcgis.com/apps/MapJournal/index.html?appid=e60e956c9f304027802e9bef6177fac1

Technologies used: Web appBuilder, ArcGIS Online

Description: This project provides Melbourne Water's land asset information in a map environment and allows the public to launch an **expression of interest**(ArcGIS Online's GeoForm) to develop community parks, schools etc and allows users to provide details about that interest and submits to a database.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Configuration & customisation of widgets and themes using Web appBuilder for ArcGIS.
- Configuration of a GeoForm for user's to express their location of interest on the map, creating Story Map Journal and exposing the story of the map by hosting it in ArcGIS Online.

SDI (Spatial Data Infrastructure) Support — *GIS*

Description: This project stores all the Melbourne water business data and management of this data such as loading data from third party businesses, and distributing data to all the systems in Melbourne Water.

Technologies used: ArcGIS Desktop, Portal for ArcGIS, ArcGIS Server, Oracle, Map Info Tool

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Monitoring Data Refresh activities where BizTalk acts as a middleware to process the request and response from the other systems.
- Configuring users emails in Oracle database Schema to route the daily data refresh activity log files into their mailbox.
- Worked on topology issues using Map Info Professional tool where data is having self-intersection, OGC validations.